<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<part n="1">
   First Mission

    [MD1STIN: Platform] Sector 1 train station

    C'mon newcomer. Follow me.

        Check fallen guards, you can do this twice to get two items

        Received "Potion"!

    Go forward

    Battle: MP x2

    Who goes there!?

    Join group through doorway

    [MD1_1: Sector 1 Station] In front of gate

    Biggs:
    	

    Wow! You used to be in SOLDIER all right! ...Not everyday ya find one in a group like AVALANCHE.

    Jessie:
    	

    SOLDIER? Aren't they the enemy?

    Jessie:
    	

    What's he doing with us in AVALANCHE?

    Biggs:
    	

    Hold it, Jessie. He WAS in SOLDIER.

    He quit them and now is one of us.

    Biggs:
    	

    Didn't catch your name...

    Name Cloud

    Cloud:
    	

    ...Cloud.

    Biggs:
    	

    Cloud, eh? I'm...

    Cloud:
    	

    I don't care what your names are. Once this job's over...I'm outta here.

    The hell you all doin'!? I thought I told you never to move in a group!

    Our target's the North Mako Reactor. We'll meet on the bridge in front of it.

    Ex-SOLDIER, huh? Don't trust ya!

    Name Barret

    Barret:
    	

    If you push the Directional button while pushing the [CANCEL] button to run. (earlier marked [X])

    Follow group through the gate and continue inside

    [MD1_2: Sector 1] Streets leading up to the reactor. No dialogue.

    [NRTHMK: No.1 Reactor] T-shaped walkway

        Talk to Wedge

        Wedge:
        	

        I'll secure the escape passage. Concentrate on the mission, Cloud.

        Wedge:
        	

        Geez, we're really gonna blow this huge furnace up? This'll be somethin' to see!

    [NMKIN_1: No.1 Reactor] Control room with locked doors

    Barret:
    	

    Yo! This your first time in a reactor?

    Cloud:
    	

    No. After all, I did work for Shinra, y'know.

    Barret:
    	

    The planet's full of Mako energy. People here use it every day.

    But none of 'em know what it really is. How 'bout you?

    Barret:
    	

    It's the life blood of this planet. But Shinra keeps suckin' the blood out with these weird machines.

    Cloud:
    	

    I'm not here for a lecture. Let's just hurry.

    Barret:
    	

    That's it! You're comin' with me from now on.

    Barret:
    	

    Now let's go into the reactor! From here on out, you stick with me.

    Leave this to me!

    Don't mess up SOLDIER-boy!

    Bring Barret back alive!

    Put Barret in back row, talk to Biggs

    If first door has not been deciphered

        Biggs:
        	

        Code deciphered

    Otherwise

        Biggs:
        	

        Think how many of our people risked their lives, just for this code...

    Talk to Jessie

    If first door has not been deciphered

        Jessie:
        	

        Biggs and I got the code for this door.

    If first door has been deciphered, but second door has not

        Jessie:
        	

        Code deciphered

        Check chest in lower right room

        Received "Phoenix Down"!

    Talk to Jessie, follow her into elevator

    [ELEVTR1: No.1 Reactor] Inside the elevator

    Jessie:
    	

    Push that button over there!

    Push switch

    Switch On.

    Barret:
    	

    Little by little the reactors'll drain out all the life. And that'll be that.

    Cloud:
    	

    It's not my problem.

    Barret:
    	

    The planet's dyin', Cloud!

    Cloud:
    	

    The only thing I care about is finishin' this job before security and the Roboguards come.

    Follow Jessie, talk to her

    [NMKIN_3: No.1 Reactor] Service access area with ladders

    Jessie:
    	

    Push the [OK] button in front of a ladder to grab on to it. After that, use the [Directional button] to move up and down.

    Go down ladder, continue down

    [NMKIN_5: No.1 Reactor] Reactor core

    Check the item on the ground

    Received "Restore" Materia!

    Cloud:
    	

    This is...... Materia...

    Continue forward

    Barret:
    	

    When we blow this place, this ain't gonna be nothin' more than a hunka junk.

    Barret:
    	

    Cloud, you set the bomb.

    Cloud:
    	

    Shouldn't you do it?

    Barret:
    	

    Jus' do it! I gotta watch to make sure you don't pull nothin'.

    Cloud:
    	

    Fine, be my guest.

    Watch out! This isn't just a reactor!!

    Barret:
    	

    ......What's wrong?

    Cloud:
    	

    Huh?

    Barret:
    	

    What's wrong, Cloud? Hurry it up!

    Cloud:
    	

    ...Yeah, sorry.

    Barret:
    	

    Heads up, here they come!

    Boss is weak against lightning but immune to gravity. It has a strong counterattack when its tail is raised. Win Assault Gun.

    Battle: Guard Scorpion

        First and third turns

            Locked On Target

        After 4 turns

            If Cloud is alive

                If Barret is also alive

                    Cloud "Barret, be careful!"

                If Barret is dead

                    Cloud "It's gonna fire that laser..."

                Attack while it's tail's up!

                It's gonna counterattack with its laser.

            If Cloud is dead

                Barret "I dunno what's goin' on, but..."

                it looks pretty bad.

                Let's see what it does when it's tail's up...

    Cloud:
    	

    Come on, let's get outta here!

    Ten minutes to detonation!

    Cloud:
    	

    The alarm!

    Two minutes remaining

    One minute remaining

    Thirty seconds remaining

    Ten seconds remaining

    Five seconds remaining

    Four seconds remaining

    Three seconds remaining

    Two seconds remaining

    One second remaining

    Equip Barret with Assault Gun, retrace path up

The Way Back

    [NMKIN_3: No.1 Reactor] Service access area with ladders

    Check item in front of Jessie

    Received "Potion"!

    Talk to Jessie

    Cloud:
    	

    You all right?

    Jessie:
    	

    My leg got stuck.

    Jessie:
    	

    Thanks!

    Go back to the top and talk to Jessie

    [NMKIN_1: No.1 Reactor] Control room with locked doors

    If second door has not been deciphered

        Jessie:
        	

        Code deciphered

    Otherwise

        Jessie:
        	

        Alright, be careful.

    Talk to Biggs

    If you didn't help free Jessie's leg

        Biggs:
        	

        Jessie still hasn't come up yet!

    If second door has been deciphered, but first door has not

        Biggs:
        	

        Code deciphered

    Otherwise

        Biggs:
        	

        Let's go!

    Biggs:
    	

    Just let my guard down for a minute... And the enemy got behind me...

    Can't decipher code without Jessie

    Can't decipher code without Biggs

    Get out of the reactor

    [MD8_4] Inside tunnel sealed by debris

    Biggs:
    	

    That should keep the planet going... at least a little longer.

    Wedge:
    	

    Yeah.

    Barret:
    	

    .........

    Jessie:
    	

    OK! Now everyone get back.

    [MD8_1: Sector 8] Outside tunnel

    Barret:
    	

    All right, now let's get out of here.

    Barret:
    	

    Rendezvous at Sector 8 station! Split up and get on the train!

    Cloud:
    	

    H, hey!

    Barret:
    	

    If it's about your money Save it 'til we're back at the hideout.

    Follow Barret up stairs

    [MD8_2] Streets

    Flower girl:
    	

    Excuse me.

    Flower girl:
    	

    What happened?

        You'd better get out of here

            Flower girl:
            	

            Really? I don't know what's going on, but all right.

        Nothing...hey, listen...

            Cloud:
            	

            ............

                Don't see many flowers around here

                    Flower girl:
                    	

                    Oh, these? Do you like them? They're only a gil...?

                Never mind

                    Flower girl:
                    	

                    What! Tell me!

                    Flower girl:
                    	

                    Uh,excuse me,would you like to buy some flowers? They're only one gil.

                Buy one

                    Choose this if you want to date Tifa/Barret

                    Flower girl:
                    	

                    Oh, thank you!

                    Flower girl:
                    	

                    Here you are!

                Forget it

                    Choose this if you want to date Aeris/Yuffie

                    Flower girl:
                    	

                    Ahh...not again.

    What an explosion!

    Think it's another Mako reactor accident?

    Continue down

    [MD8_3] Square with a fountain in the middle

        Talk to the person walking

        Just what the hell's going on!?

        Talk to the person standing

        Wonder what that is on the wall over there. Let's see...

        Don't be fooled by Shinra! Mako energy doesn't last forever! Mako is the planet's lifesource! The end is in sight!

        Protectors of the planet: AVALANCHE

        Check item on the left side

        Received "Potion"!

    A paper hung on the wall

    Continue down street. Quickly choose "Later!" if you don't want to fight the battles.

    [MD8BRDG: Sector 8] Street overlooking train tracks

    Soldier:
    	

    Hey! You there!!

    Cloud:
    	

    Shinra Soldiers......

        Fight them!

            Battle: MP x2

            What the?

            Cloud:
            	

            hmph!

        Later!

            Soldier:
            	

            Halt!!

        Fight them!

            Battle: MP x3

            Soldier:
            	

            That's him!!

            Cloud:
            	

            hmph!

        Later!

        Fight them!

            Battle: MP x3 (from both sides)

            Soldier:
            	

            Over here!!

            Cloud:
            	

            hmph!

        Later!

    Soldier:
    	

    That's as far as you go.

    Cloud:
    	

    I don't have time to be messin' around with you guys.

    Soldier:
    	

    Enough babbling...... Grab him!!

    Cloud:
    	

    What a pain......

Train Ride

    [CARGOIN: Last Train from Midgar] Cargo car on the train

    Wedge:
    	

    Cloud never came.

    Biggs:
    	

    Cloud...... Wonder if he was killed?

    Barret:
    	

    No way!!

    Ain't no way he'd ever disappear without getting his money!!

    Jessie:
    	

    Cloud......

    Biggs:
    	

    Say, do you think Cloud's......

    Going to fight to the end for AVALANCHE!?

    Barret:
    	

    The hell would I know!? Do I look like a mind reader?

    Hmph!! If y'all weren't such screw-ups...

    We wouldn't be needin' to hire guys like him......

    Wedge:
    	

    Hey, Barret! What about our money...?

    Uh, nothin'...sorry.

    Ahhh......

    Wedge:
    	

    Cloud!!

    Biggs:
    	

    Cloud!!

    Jessie:
    	

    Cloud......

    Cloud:
    	

    Looks like I'm a little late.

    Barret:
    	

    You damn right, you're late!!

    Come waltzin' in here makin' a big scene!

    Cloud:
    	

    It's no big deal. Just what I always do.

    Barret:
    	

    Shi't!

    Havin' everyone worried like that you don't give a damn 'bout no one but yourself!

    Cloud:
    	

    Hmm...... You were worried about me!

    Barret:
    	

    Wha!?

    I'm takin' it outta your money, hot stuff!

    Barret:
    	

    Wake up!

    We're movin' out! Follow me!

    Wedge:
    	

    Hey, Cloud!! You were great back there!

    Biggs:
    	

    Heh heh......Cloud! We'll do even better next time.

    Jessie:
    	

    Be careful, I'll shut this.

    Jessie:
    	

    Oh, Cloud!! Your face is pitch-black......

    Jessie:
    	

    There you go!

    Jessie:
    	

    Say, thanks for helping me back there at the Reactor!

    Cloud:
    	

    Yeah......

        That's OK

            Cloud:
            	

            Don't mention it.

            Jessie:
            	

            But, I...... I was just glad...

        Quit thanking me

            Cloud:
            	

            It bugs me when you thank me. It's just a part of my job.

            Jessie:
            	

            Cloud......

            You're right. We're just work friends...

    Cloud:
    	

    It's not ready yet...... Whoa......!!

    Shut-off the switch in this position.

    We can escape from the train event...... Did it!! 4th failure 3rd failure 2nd failure 1st failure Escaped

    Follow Jessie

    [TIN_1: Last Train from Midgar] Passenger car on the train

    This is the end of the Test Play.

    Last train out of Sector 8 Station. Last stop is Sector 7, Train Graveyard. Expected time of arrival is 12:23AM, Midgar Standard Time...

    This is why I hate the last train. Hoo-boy...

        Talk to the man sleeping on the right

        Huh...? This is my house, so make yourselves at home.

        Talk to the man sitting on the left

        You see the headlines in the Shinra Times?

        The terrorists that bombed the No. 1 Reactor are based somewhere in the slums.

        ...blowing up a Reactor... they sure put some thought into this one.

        They must have a real calculating leader. I wonder what they'll do next?

        Talk to Barret

        Barret:
        	

        Stop actin' like a damn kid. Si'down an' shu'up!

        Talk to Biggs

        Biggs:
        	

        It seems this train hasn't switched to security mode yet.

        I'm sure that will change by tomorrow.

        Talk to Biggs again

        Biggs:
        	

        ...YAWN...that sure took its toll on me. I'm gonna sleep till we get to the station.

        Talk to Wedge

        Wedge:
        	

        Someday AVALANCHE's gonna be famous ...and me, too!

        Talk to Wedge again

        Wedge:
        	

        Cloud!!

        Don't ya think I got a bright future ahead of me?

            What do you have in mind?

                Wedge:
                	

                All my life, I felt like nothin' but a sidekick.

                But, after joinin' AVALANCHE and tryin' to save the Planet, I feel like I can do lots of things.

            I wouldn't hold my breath

                Wedge:
                	

                Oh man, that's pretty harsh, Cloud. You really think I won't?

        Try to go into next car

        Please!! You're bothering the other passengers.

    Hey!! What's going on here...!?

    Oops, uh, n, nothing...

    Please don't make any trouble.

    ...mumble...grumble... (...Reactor's blown to bits... ...Bad things just never seem to stop... ...What a day!)

    To the Route Map Screen

    Talk to Jessie

    Jessie:
    	

    Hey, Cloud. You want to look at this with me?

    It's a map of the Midgar Rail System. Let's look at it together. I'll explain it to you.

    Jessie:
    	

    I like this kinda stuff. Bombs and monitors...you know, flashy stuff.

    [ROOTMAP: Last Train from Midgar] Screen showing an animation of Midgar's structure

    Jessie:
    	

    Okay, it's about to start.

    Jessie:
    	

    This is a complete model of the city of Midgar.

    It's about a 1/10000 scale.

    The top plate is about 50 meters above ground.

    A main support structure holds the plate up in the center, and there are other support structures built in each section...

    psst...whisper...whisper... (The No. 1 Reactor we blew up was in the northern section.)

    Then there's No.2, No.3 all the way up to the No.8 Reactor.

    The 8 Reactors provide Midgar with electricity.

    Each town used to have a name, but no one in Midgar remembers them.

    Instead of names, we refer to them by numbered sectors. That's the kind of place this is.

    Jessie:
    	

    Phew..., this is next! Look.

    Jessie:
    	

    This is the route this train is on.

    The route spirals around the main support structure.

    We should be coming around the center area, right now.

    At each checkpoint, an ID sensor device is set up.

    It can check the identities and background on each and every passenger on the train by linking it up to the central data bank at Shinra headquarters.

    whisper...whisper... (Anyone could tell that we look suspicious, so we're using fake ID's.)

    Jessie:
    	

    Cloud! Look this way.

    [TIN_1: Last Train from Midgar] Passenger car

    Jessie:
    	

    Speak of the devil...

    That light means that we're in the ID Security Check area.

    ...whisper...whisper... (When the lights go off, you never know what kind of creeps'll come out.)

    ...anyhow, we're almost back now. That's a relief.

        Talk to Biggs

        Biggs:
        	

        ...snore...heebeebeeheebee...snore... (Don't act so damn big, Barret...snooze...)

        Talk to Wedge

        Wedge:
        	

        I'm seein' stars. This sucks. I hate the dark.

        Talk to Jessie

        Jessie:
        	

        I know!

        Next time, I'll give you one I made myself.

            Thanks anyway

                Jessie:
                	

                Oh yeah, you might regret it. I'm the type who takes things personal.

            Looking forward to it

                Choose this if you want to date Aeris/Yuffie/Barret

                Jessie:
                	

                Okay, then I'll put a little extra effort in and make it with a BANG.

        Talk to Jessie again

        Jessie:
        	

        We're almost there. After talking with you, I really want to do it!

        I think you've lit my fuse!

    Walk toward Barret

    Barret:
    	

    Look...you can see the surface now. This city don't have no day or night.

    If that plate weren't there... we could see the sky.

    Cloud:
    	

    A floating city... Pretty unsettling scenery.

    Barret:
    	

    Huh?

    Never expect ta hear that outta someone like you.

    ...you jes' full of surprises.

    Barret:
    	

    The upper world...a city on a plate...

    It's 'cuz of that &^#$# 'pizza', that people underneath are sufferin'!

    Barret:
    	

    All the pollution from Mako energy above falls down on the world below.

    Barret:
    	

    And the city below is full of polluted air.

    Barret:
    	

    On topa that, the Reactor keeps drainin' up all the energy.

    'Cuz of that, the land withers away. It ain't even got the power to clean up the air.

    Cloud:
    	

    Then why doesn't everyone move onto the Plate?

    Barret:
    	

    Dunno. Probably 'cuz they ain't got no money. Or, maybe...

    'Cuz they love their land, no matter how polluted it gets.

    Cloud:
    	

    I know... no one lives in the slums because they want to.

    It's like this train. It can't run anywhere except where its rails take it.

Arrival

    [MDS7ST3: Sector 7 Station]

    Barret:
    	

    Yo!! Get over here, all'ya!!

        Walk toward the right side

        Barret:
        	

        Yo, Cloud! You lissen up!

    Barret:
    	

    Yo! What'chu doin' now!

    Walk down toward Barret

    Barret:
    	

    This mission was a success. But don't get lazy now.

    The hard part's still to come! Don't y'all be scared of that explosion!

    Barret:
    	

    Cause the next one's gonna be bigger than that!

    Barret:
    	

    Meet back at the hideout!! Move out!

    Tifa:
    	

    Cloud... Don't be so distant. Everyone wants to be your friend. I'm sure...

    Barret:
    	

    Damn, man!! I'm here to fight! Don't care 'bout bein' nobody's friend.

    Barret:
    	

    Let's go! Don't be late!

    Biggs:
    	

    uh, Barret... We, uh...

    Wedge:
    	

    We can't do it. We just can't do it.

    Jessie:
    	

    Don't worry! Don't get all worried!

    Jessie:
    	

    Cloud! Let's make the mission work!

    Jessie:
    	

    Cloud...? When this mission's over...

    Why don't all of us take a long vacation. I don't know......

        Maybe we could go to a hot springs somewhere?

            Cloud:
            	

            Yeah...... If I feel like it.

            Jessie:
            	

            Alrighty then! It's a date!

        Yeah......

            Cloud:
            	

            You never know what lies ahead.

            Jessie:
            	

            ...how lovely. I might just have to tempt you, then.

    Barret:
    	

    Yo, you all done flappin' your gums!? Go! Get on that train!

    More optional dialogue is available in Sector 7. Follow group, talk to Barret when ready.

    [MDS7: Sector 7 Slums] Main area of Sector 7 with houses

    If Tifa hasn't gone inside yet

        First time

            Barret:
            	

            Heh heh...

            You wanna meet your little baby?

                Little baby?

                    Barret:
                    	

                    Hey! Don' act like you don't know what I mean!

                    I'm tellin' you...

                Out of my way!

                    Barret:
                    	

                    Heh! Jes calm down.

                    Can't have people suspectin' us.

        Afterwards

            Barret:
            	

            Heh! Jes calm down.

            Can't have people suspectin' us.

    After Tifa goes inside

        Barret:
        	

        Ok! Go on ahead.

        Talk to Barret again after he lets you in, or just wait a few seconds

        Barret:
        	

        You! Cloud!! Get off your slow-movin' ass!!

    Barret:
    	

    All right!! You losers go on ahead!!

    Barret:
    	

    The hell're you doin', boy? The operation's already started!!

    Go into bar

7th Heaven

    [MDS7PB_1: 7th Heaven] Inside the bar

    Papa!!

    Marlene! Aren't you going to say anything to Cloud?

    Welcome home, Cloud. Looks like everything went well.

    Did you fight with Barret?

        Yeah

            I should have known.

            He's always pushing people around, and you've always been in fights ever since you were little.

            I was worried.

        Not this time

            Hmm. You've grown up.

            When you were little you used to get into fights at the drop of a hat.

    Name Tifa

    If you bought flower from Aeris

        Tifa:
        	

        Flowers? How nice...

        You almost never see them here in the slums.

        Tifa:
        	

        But...

        A flower for me? Oh Cloud, you shouldn't have...

        Cloud:
        	

        No big.

            Give it to Tifa

                Choose this if you want to date Tifa

                Tifa:
                	

                Thank you, Cloud. It smells wonderful.

                Maybe I should fill the store with flowers.

                Tifa:
                	

                Cloud, this one still has roots. I can probably start others from it.

            Give it to Marlene

                Choose this if you want to date Barret

    Otherwise

        Tifa:
        	

        I'm so glad everyone's safe.

        Talk to Biggs

        Biggs:
        	

        Aaah!! Nothin' like that first drink after a job.

        Biggs:
        	

        Hic!!

        Why don't you have one too?

            No

                What!? You tellin' me you're too good to drink with me?

                Don't act big-headed jus' because you were in SOLDIER!

            Yeah, why not?

                Biggs:
                	

                Oh!! That's more like it!!

                Even if you were with SOLDIER, you're still a rookie here. So you'd better listen to whatever I tell ya!

        Talk to Biggs again

        Biggs:
        	

        Hic...!!

        Oh...... Don't tell Barret what I jus said.

    Biggs:
    	

    You know, Cloud. Barret says those things, but......

    We're really unstable right now. If SOLDIER were to show up, they'd whup us.

        Talk to Wedge

        Wedge:
        	

        Oh, Cloud!

        Tifa really knows how to cook. Mmm, mmm......

        Anyway, let me tell you somethin'

            About what?

                Tifa always lets me taste her cooking.

                And look at me now, I'm rolly-polly.

                Don't know whether I should be happy or sad. But it's the good food and drinks that make this shop famous.

            I'm not interested in your stories

                Cloud...... ......forget it.

    Wedge:
    	

    Cloud, ya gotta help us. I'm really scared.

        Talk to Jessie

        Jessie:
        	

        Careless...... You're getting all excited.

        Wonder what for......?

    Jessie:
    	

    Cloud...... It's painful.

    Why is that?

        Talk to Marlene

        Marlene:
        	

        ............

        Talk to Tifa

        Tifa:
        	

        Sorry, Cloud. Marlene seems a little shy.

    enter name

    Try to go outside

    Marlene:
    	

    Papa, welcome home!

    If Marlene got flower

        Barret:
        	

        Yeah.

        Barret:
        	

        Huh? Where'd you get that flower?

        Marlene:
        	

        Cloud gave it to me.

        Barret:
        	

        Oh......

        Barret:
        	

        Did you thank him?

        ............

        Marlene:
        	

        Thank you, Cloud.

        We'll take care of you.

    Tifa:
    	

    You all right, Barret?

    Barret:
    	

    Great!!

    Barret:
    	

    Get in here, fools!! We're startin' the meetin'!!

        Approach bar stools

        Tifa:
        	

        Sit down.

        Tifa:
        	

        How about...

        ...something to drink?

            I don't feel like it

                Tifa:
                	

                OHH!!

                I can make a drink just as good as anyone else.

                Everyone says, my drinks taste the best!

            Give me something hard

                Choose this if you want to date Tifa

                Tifa:
                	

                Just a minute. I'll make one for you.

                Tifa:
                	

                You know, I'm relieved you made it back safely.

                Cloud:
                	

                What's with you all of a sudden? That wasn't even a tough job.

                Tifa:
                	

                I guess not...

                You were in SOLDIER.

                Tifa:
                	

                Make sure you get your pay from Barret.

                Cloud:
                	

                Don't worry. Once I get that money, I'm outta here.

        Tifa:
        	

        Cloud. Are you feeling all right?

        Cloud:
        	

        ...yeah... Why?

        Tifa:
        	

        No reason. You just look a little tired I guess.

        Talk to Tifa

        If she hasn't offered you a drink yet

            Tifa:
            	

            Cloud... come over here.

        Otherwise

            Tifa:
            	

            You'd better go down below.

    Tifa:
    	

    Everyone is down below.

    Marlene:
    	

    ..................

    New optional dialogue is available in Sector 7. Ride the pinball machine downstairs when ready.

Debriefing

    [MDS7PB_2: AVALANCHE Hideout] Basement of the bar

        Check TV

        President Shinra:
        	

        .........today the No.1 Reactor was bombed. The terrorist group AVALANCHE has claimed responsibility for the bombing.

        It is expected that AVALANCHE will continue its reign of terror.

        But citizens of Midgar, there is no need to fear.

        I have immediately mobilized SOLDIER to protect our citizenry against this senseless violence. Thank you and good night.

        Talk to Wedge

        Wedge:
        	

        You think I'm a little too uptight?

            Yeah...

                The next mission will be to blow up the Sector 5 Reactor.

                Cloud, you're great! Don't you ever get nervous?

                Or are you like, impervious to feelings? Naw, that couldn't be it.

            No...

                Well, that's ok. Don't worry about me. I don't look like it, but I'm a coward at heart.

        Talk to Jessie

        Jessie:
        	

        Oops...

        Hey, look at the news... What a blast.

        Think it was all because of my bomb? But all I really did was just make it like the computer told me.

        Oh no! I must've made a miscalculation somewhere.

        Talk to Jessie again

        Jessie:
        	

        Hey, that was my bomb's debut. Makes me kinda proud.

    Approach Barret

    Barret:
    	

    Yo, Cloud! There's somethin' I wanna ask ya.

    Was there anyone from SOLDIER fighting us today?

    Cloud:
    	

    None. I'm positive.

    Barret:
    	

    You sound pretty sure.

    Cloud:
    	

    If there was anyone from SOLDIER you wouldn't be standing here now.

    Barret:
    	

    Don't go thinkin' you so bad jes cuz you was in SOLDIER.

    Cloud:
    	

    ............

    Barret:
    	

    Yeah, you're strong.

    Probably all them guys in SOLDIER are.

    But don't forget that your skinny ass's workin' for AVALANCHE now!

    Don't get no ideas 'bout hangin' on to Shinra.

    Cloud:
    	

    Stayin' with Shinra?

    You asked me a question and I answered it...that's all.

    Cloud:
    	

    I'm going upstairs. I want to talk about my money.

        Talk to Barret

        Barret:
        	

        Shucks!! ............money...

        Talk to Marlene

        Marlene:
        	

        Papa, you're so great!

    Go back toward pinball machine

    Tifa:
    	

    Wait, Cloud!

    Barret:
    	

    Tifa! Let him go!

    Looks like he still misses the Shinra!

    Cloud:
    	

    Shut up!

    I don't care about either Shinra or SOLDIER!

    But don't get me wrong!

    I don't care about AVALANCHE or the Planet for that matter!

        Talk to Wedge

        Wedge:
        	

        .......Cloud.

        You say you don't care, but you came to talk to me.

        Cloud... You just want friends.

        Isn't that right?

            Blow off

                Yeah, well. You look kind of lonely to me.

                If you ever got anything you want to get off your chest, you can always talk to me.

            I really don't care

                You're terrible. Real cold blooded.

        Talk to Jessie

        Jessie:
        	

        Money...

        Oh my. It must have been for a lot of it.

        Sure! Well, what the hell? It's a verbal agreement. Now let me figure this out.

        Oh stop it, Cloud! Did you hear me?

        Talk to Tifa

        Tifa:
        	

        Straighten things up with everyone for me.

    Go upstairs, try to leave

Childhood Promise

    [MDS7PB_1: 7th Heaven]

    Tifa:
    	

    Listen, Cloud. I'm asking you. Please join us.

    Cloud:
    	

    Sorry Tifa...

    Tifa:
    	

    The Planet is dying. Slowly but surely it's dying.

    Someone has to do something.

    Cloud:
    	

    So let Barret and his buddies do something about it.

    It's got nothin' to do with me.

    Barret:
    	

    You damn right we'll do something about it. N' you stay outta this Tifa!

    Tifa:
    	

    So! You're really leaving !?

    Tifa:
    	

    You're just going to walk right out ignoring your childhood friend !?

    Cloud:
    	

    What......?

        How can you say that!

            Choose this if you want to date Tifa

        ......Sorry

            Choose this if you want to date Aeris/Yuffie/Barret

    Tifa:
    	

    Please Cloud...

    Tifa:
    	

    Cloud... I can't believe this is goodbye.

    Tifa:
    	

    ......You forgot the promise, too.

    Cloud:
    	

    Promise?

    Tifa:
    	

    So you DID forget.

    Tifa:
    	

    Remember......Cloud. It was seven years ago...

    [NIVL_E1] Flashback scene by the well in Nibelheim

    Tifa:
    	

    Look, the well.

    Do you remember?

    Cloud:
    	

    Yeah...back then.

    Cloud:
    	

    I thought you would never come, and I was getting a little cold.

    Tifa:
    	

    Sorry I'm late.

    Tifa:
    	

    You said you wanted to talk to me about something?

    Cloud:
    	

    Come this spring...I'm leaving this town for Midgar.

    Tifa:
    	

    ...All boys are leaving our town.

    Cloud:
    	

    But I'm different from all of them. I'm not just going to find a job.

    Cloud:
    	

    I want to join SOLDIER.

    Cloud:
    	

    I'm going to be the best there is, just like Sephiroth!

    Tifa:
    	

    Sephiroth... The Great Sephiroth.

    Cloud:
    	

    I thought about Sephiroth all the time. Even in my sleep. My mom just gave up on me.

    Tifa:
    	

    I had no idea you were thinking that way...

    Tifa:
    	

    But, what about our promise?

    Tifa:
    	

    Isn't it hard to join SOLDIER?

    Cloud:
    	

    ...I probably won't be able to come back to this town for a while.

    Cloud:
    	

    ...huh?

    Tifa:
    	

    Will you be in the newspapers if you do well?

    Cloud:
    	

    I'll try.

    Tifa:
    	

    Hey, why don't we make a promise?

    Tifa:
    	

    Umm, if you get really famous and I'm ever in a bind......

    You come save me, all right?

    Cloud:
    	

    What?

    Tifa:
    	

    Whenever I'm in trouble, my hero will come and rescue me.

    I want to at least experience that once.

    Cloud:
    	

    What?

    Cloud:
    	

    Ha, ha, ha! What's that!

    Tifa:
    	

    You're laughing at me!

    Tifa:
    	

    Come on--! Promise me----!

    Cloud:
    	

    All right......I promise.

    [MDS7PB_1: 7th Heaven] End flashback

    Tifa:
    	

    You remember now, don't you... our promise?

    Cloud:
    	

    I'm not a hero and I'm not famous. I can't keep......the promise.

    Tifa:
    	

    But you got your childhood dream, didn't you? You joined SOLDIER.

    Tifa:
    	

    So come on! You've got to keep your promise......

    Barret:
    	

    Wait a sec big-time SOLDIER!

    Barret:
    	

    Whoa, wait a damn minute. Cloud!!

    Barret:
    	

    A promise is a promise! Here!!

    Barret:
    	

    There's your money. Now get the hell out!!

    Received Barret's stash, 1500 gil!

    Cloud:
    	

    This is my pay? Don't make me laugh.

    Tifa:
    	

    What? Then you'll...!!

    Cloud:
    	

    You got the next mission lined up? I'll do it for 3000.

    Barret:
    	

    What......!?

    Tifa:
    	

    It's ok, it's ok.

    Tifa:
    	

    psst, psst...... (We're really hurting for help, right?)

    Barret:
    	

    Uh......ugh...... (That money's for Marlene's schoolin'......)

    Barret:
    	

    2000!

    Tifa:
    	

    Thanks, Cloud.

    Tifa:
    	

    Will you please come back? Ah, wait. Please wait.

    The president of Shinra is going to read a statement.

    President Shinra:
    	

    The terrorist group called AVALANCHE has claimed responsibility for today's bombing of the No.1 Mako Reactor.

    It is also predicted that they will continue with similar terrorist activities in the future.

    But I want the citizens of Midgar to be assured.

    Shinra, Inc. has mobilized SOLDIER to protect you from any violence and thereby......

    Tifa:
    	

    The next time we'll be up against...SOLDIER.

    Tifa:
    	

    Cloud, then you'll help us?

        A promise is a promise

            Tifa:
            	

            I hate Barret.

        But I still hate Barret

            If this is the first time you answer this

                Tifa:
                	

                You came to tell me that?

            If this is the second time you answer this

                Tifa:
                	

                He's not a bad person.

            If this is the third time you answer this

                Tifa:
                	

                Don't worry. I'll talk to him.

            The first two times you pick this answer, Tifa will ask you the same question again

    Tifa:
    	

    Come on. Let's go below!

    Go back upstairs after sleeping

The Next Morning

    [MDS7PB_1: 7th Heaven]

        Talk to Tifa. Don't do this if you want to date Aeris or Yuffie.

        Tifa:
        	

        Good Morning! Cloud!

        Did you sleep well?

            Barret's snoring kept me up......

                Choose this if you want to date Barret

                Tifa:
                	

                psstpsst...

                (keep it down, they'll hear you. Barret's always edgy before an operation.)

            Next to you, who wouldn't?

                Choose this if you want to date Tifa

                Tifa:
                	

                I don't know what you mean.

        Tifa:
        	

        I'm going this time.

    Talk to Barret

    Barret:
    	

    Our target's the Sector 5 Reactor. Head for the station first.

    I'll fill you in on the train.

    Barret:
    	

    Yo! Cloud!

    Before the next mission, I got somethin' I wanna ask you!

    I, uh,...... I don't really know how to use Materia!

    I'll give you that Materia you found. Just teach me how to use it!

    Cloud:
    	

    ...sigh...

        Ok, I'll explain it

            Sure, I'll explain how Materia works.

            First, access the menu.

            You know the basic functions.

            The triangle button brings up the menu.

            Directional buttons move the cursor,

            like this.

            Select each menu by using the OK button.

            If you want to leave the menu,

            just push the CANCEL button.

            See? Let's go ahead.

            Now you're in this menu.

            Select [Materia] sub menu.

            Select who you want to use it.

            Now look at my weapon here.

            Each weapon and armor has slots in it.

            Choose which slot you want to put Materia in.

            Now select the Materia you want to use.

            This is curative Materia.

            If you want to know what its effect is,

            line the cursor up with [Check],

            and push the OK button.

            It's just like selecting battle commands.

            Just line the cursor up to [Magic],

            you can see that the available magic has increased.

            Now you can use new magic [Cure].

            And that's all there is to equipping Materia.

            See? It wasn't that tough!

            When you want to remove any Materia,

            it's as easy as pointing to the materia slot,

            and pushing the triangle button.

            There's just one thing you have to be careful of.

            Whenever you equip Materia,

            your situation changes.

            Parts of you may become stronger...

            while others get weaker.

            Normally, when you equip [Magic] Materia,

            your magic power will get stronger.

            But your physical strength weakens.

            So, Materia's kind of a double-edged sword.

            On the left side of the screen,

            you can see the Materia's effect on you.

            It's wise not to overuse Magic Materia.

            But try out various things.

            Push the CANCEL button to exit the sub menu.

            Ok, that's about it.

            I'll give you some advanced tips later.

            Barret:
            	

            Shi......! What's this 'It wasn't that tough!' crap!

            I'm clueless......

            Well, you handle the Materia then!

        You wouldn't understand

            Barret:
            	

            So this is what makes them guys in SOLDIER so great, huh!?

            Ok. I'll ask Jessie again later. But you're in charge of the Materia!

    [Materia System] Access the menu and select [Materia] to equip Materia.

    If you have not talked to Tifa in the morning

        Tifa:
        	

        I'm going this time.

    Tifa:
    	

    Cloud! I got a message from the Weapon Shop man upstairs.

    He has something he wants to give you. Don't forget!

    Tifa:
    	

    Marlene, you watch the store while we're gone!

    Marlene:
    	

    All right!! Good Luck.

    Barret:
    	

    Yo, Cloud.

    Got a message from the old man at the weapon shop upstairs!

    Said he's got somethin' special so come and get it!

    Yo! If you pull somethin' funny... You now what I'll do to ya, right?

    Yo! Try somethin' funny... An' you know what I'm gonna do, right!?

        Talk to Marlene

        Marlene:
        	

        Take care!

    Thudthudthud!! That ???? is supposed to come in.

    Cloud:
    	

    What's goin' on...? It's really shakin' a lot......

    Cloud:
    	

    Tifa......? Tifa...? Where?

    Cloud:
    	

    ...I'm going out......

    New optional dialogue is available in Sector 7 and Beginner's Hall. New optional items can be picked up in Beginner's Hall. Do some shopping, and board the train when ready.
    
 </part>